Chris: So, what exactly is
Kanban and how does it work?
Leah: Kanban first came about in Japan.
The Japanese word ‘Kanban’ translates
as ‘signboard’ or ‘visual card’.
In the 1940s it was developed [with LEAN
methodology] by an engineer for Toyota.
It was predominately used in
‘just-in-time’ manufacturing.
Kanban came to the attention of the
software industry and is nowadays
used in the Agile methodology.
The objective of Kanban is to simplify
planning, manage work and inventory, and
increase productivity and efficiency.
Chris: Kanban is a visual system,
and the flow of work is managed
using a Kanban project board.
Often these same types of project boards
are used in Agile and Scrum methodology.
In its simplest form there are
three columns which are labelled:
‘To Do’, ‘In Progress’, and ‘Done’.
These labels would be different
depending on the type of project,
so for example a Scrum Kanban board
could have more columns and could
include Stories, Current iteration,
In Progress, Tested, and Delivered.
So how does this work in practice?
Leah: A task is put on a
card and placed on the board.
Each card has a priority
and a team member.
As the task is assigned, worked
on, and completed, it is moved
from one column to the next.
As the cards move across the
board, you can identify issues
at each stage of the process.
When all task cards are in the
‘Done’ column, the iteration
is marked as complete.
There are 4 principles of Kanban,
so, let’s have a look at these.
Chris: Visualise workflow
The Kanban board is the project
visual workflow as in there
would be three columns e.g.
To do, In Progress, and Done [as
we have already mentioned], with
coloured cards for each task.
These would be assigned to team
members and moved according
to their current status.
Leah: Limit work in progress [WIP]
This is where the individual tasks would
be prioritised, assigned a certain amount
of ‘points’ [time to take/complexity], and
there would be a limit on how many tasks
[workload] each team member would have.
Focus on Flow
Chris: The workflow should run
smoothly, but stoppages could be used
as opportunities for improvement.
Measurements may be used to track
and analyse such as ‘Lead time’,
‘cycle time’ and ‘workload’.
Leah: And finally Continuous improvement
The results and the Kanban system would
be monitored to determine if it works,
and if not something else should be tried.